welcome to the stoa
the stoa is a digital campfire where we
cohere
and dialogue about what matters most at
the knife's edge
of what's happening now
all right everyone welcome to the dark
stoa i am peter lindbergh
the steward of the stoa and the dark
stoa
is a place to explore existential ultra
catastrophes for the sole purpose of
reframing them in order to navigate them
and have sane pathways of action and
meaning
and the star of the evening as always is
the most dangerous man on the internet
patrick ryan um and this um
was a part of season two of the dark so
uh and um it's coming to an end and if
you were here last week or you watched
the video on youtube uh pat did
um a talk a lecture on who he was
and uh we didn't have a chance to have a
q a so today's session is going to be a
q a
um based off that talk so
what's how how's it gonna go i'm gonna
ask pat we're gonna have a conversation
for about 20 minutes and any time while
we're talking if you have a question
put it in the the chat box um this will
go on youtube so if you want me to read
on your behalf
just indicate that and most importantly
keep it clean in the chats all right so
uh
pat are you there it says no source
selected
you're you're back so it's uh i'm gonna
unmute you you're good good all right
cool
so um yeah the first uh the question
actually someone sent me an email uh
recently and they're saying uh
like peter you're such like a good faith
nice interlocutor how did you get hooked
up with this pat
ryan guy and i was being interviewed on
a podcast and someone asked the same
question
how you how do you know this pat ryan
guy so essentially jordan hall uh
emailed me and said check out this
patreon and i was intrigued
um because like from some of you know my
work i do cultural analysis and stuff
and i like categorizing people like okay
this is like somebody
from intellectual dark webs a new
atheist but i couldn't categorize pat
running
and i love it when i can't cater guys
somebody and when i was talking to pat
about this
he said uh um i think you said to me
something along the lines is that
by design you're not meant to be
categorized so
i think this may be a good place to
start and we can go and kind of some of
the stuff we touched last time
so what why why why what what do you
mean by that by design
sure um so
i hate identity i hate it i've seen
nothing but
problems come from identity it's uh
it's the idea that i i have to conform
to
a uh a very specific
i'm sorry i'm i'm fussing around with a
bunch of technical stuff that's
interfering with me
i apologize there we go my concern with
identity
is that it's always for the convenience
of the administrator
not the administrative um there's
supposedly some type of
social benefit from fitting in within
one identity of
or another for example if i if i
identify as a white male
there is some assumed category
categorical privileges that are then
splash damaged upon me
um but that implies a gaussian
distribution of such
things so what we're doing is we're no
longer talking about humans the moment
we talk about identity we're talking
about
categorical categorical adherence uh my
ability to
um fit into a category as opposed to
what my entire brain is actually doing
this entire time
that's where the fun is up here is where
you know this is where we are doing all
of our behavior
just because i could fit into a category
or not so that an advertiser can give me
better ads
or or a politician could give me better
distribution of resources
that's not the entirety of my entire my
existence i'm beyond that
we're all beyond that i think we're all
beyond pissed about it as well
so i decided to instead of say
identity is stupid i'm just going to
live a post-identity life
that's basically it and the early
internet i could do that it was all text
based
we didn't have video or images or sound
or any
any type of human signal that you could
use to justify uh
if i was 18 female in a chat room then i
was 18 female in a chat room
i'm not telling you why i was 18 female
in a chat room maybe i'm just
uh collecting information on someone or
maybe i'm just trolling or whatever i
can reinvent my identity per line
per snippet i could be 36 male
in the next sentence this is freedom to
me
because i am whatever my brain wants me
to be at any given moment for any
context and i reserve that right
and it's my right to do that it's not
even right he says i'm going to do it
period
uh you have to and you have to put force
on me to stop me from doing that and
they are trying to do that
they are trying to say here's the
categories you must fit into when you
interact on social media
here's how you're going to get censored
for being it and then this is the
content you're supposed to see
and here's a reality tunnel and there is
i i i do not like skinner boxes i don't
like cages
i am a terrible prisoner i'm the world's
worst slave
i just want to have the freedom to be
whatever
in whatever context that i'm in just so
i can be in it
and so that's how i live my life and i'm
sure it infuriates everyone around me
based on all the data that i've seen um
but
you can't just tell people to be post
identity you have to live it
and so i'm doing my best to live it
and uh last week you said that you
experienced the full spectrum of life by
age 10.
did you elaborate on that yeah uh
there are there are considerable
uh what's the old there's one second
focus i got some
tea i want to drink
um
however bad you think humans are they're
worse
now you can you can think well my
definition of a bad human is someone who
doesn't conform to my personal category
or is adjacent to this other category
and these are nice little heuristics but
let's not talk about
the human behaviors
accordance to set theory let's just talk
about human behavior as
is um we are the byproduct of
four billion years of a very complicated
game of evolution
uh some people say it's fitness some
people say it's psychology
some people say it's energy efficiency
why not all of it why can't all of those
be selection criteria
um it's it's very difficult
to state um
it's very difficult to understand the
intention behind life if we look at life
as a function why it does what it does
people can take a snippet of it they can
take a fraction of it and look
exclusively in that fraction and say oh
the purpose of life is to generate
styrofoam
maybe you know that's that's the old uh
uh george carlton uh
i think george carlton uh he you know
one of his jokes
um maybe maybe the earth wanted
styrofoam right
um so carlin that's right um so when
when i talk about humans being worse
than you can possibly imagine um i
have i've spent a lot of time dealing
with being the target of that worstness
and i've spent a lot of my time trying
to figure out why
they were this way and this is a
difficult thing for
people to explore and reconcile with
their own personal experiences
they are given bad heuristics or they're
given bad information or they're giving
convenient information
um none of that was good enough for me
because every time an explanation was
given to me about well humans are this
way because they're poor
okay so i'll go hang around some rich
people oh they're assholes too there
goes that argument
okay humans are this way because they're
christian okay i'll go hang on some
muslims
nope they're assholes too moving on
right so all these category theories
attempts to understand human uh
situations completely wrong they
completely failed they had no
descriptive power predictive power at
all period
end of conversation i had to look into
what life was actually doing
why it was doing these weird
crazy aggressive abusive things why were
we doing this to each other
um and
uh i like to think i came close to an
answer but
in order for me to even go through and
even for me to
i'm sorry i have to close something i'm
getting inundated by unlimited
go away
in order for me to
even be care about that path i had to
have been first subjected to that
worstness
and i was um there isn't a domain of
abuse you can name that i haven't
experienced
you can go to physical verbal emotional
sexual you can go to social
you can go to
[Music]
you can invent one i probably got hit by
it that's not me being a victim
that's just me i've seen the very worst
of humanity
i've lived it i've been a victim of it
i've done it to people
i've abused people as well mostly people
who deserve it
but you don't always get it right so
um i've seen
what it means to be that way and i
the answers on why we are this way are
not satisfactory to me they've never
been satisfactory and so i've been
trying to understand it
because once you can understand it you
can predict it and if you can predict
it you can avoid the abuse if you can
avoid the abuse you can actually stop it
because that gives you the time to
actually strike back
so basically short answer is i've
i've experienced all of it
can you tease out some of the um the
insights that uh
informed you from having that full
spectrum life experience by age ten
and you said something uh in the last
presentation that you have a keen
understanding of female psychology
and i want to elaborate on that as well
yeah that's that's a that's always one
of those claims you make and there's a
bunch of
libertarians on reddit who are going
well now wait a minute
you know this type of stuff um but the
uh
i uh
uh my mother was a pile of trash still
remains one to be fair
she's a walking pile of trash and
she's doing her best to be better
um but i had to put her on that road i
had to
literally force her on that road and uh
there was no way to
there's no way to fix her uh why why was
she this way
i know why i can explain precisely why
she was that way her father died
her father was her best friend father
died in a chemical plant
from years and years of working there
from cancer um
at the age of 50 or heart failure or
something something that involved just
working with chemicals way too long
in a period in which those cyber
protections did not exist so yeah i can
explain that socioeconomically that's
easy put on you know give me my
sociology points i did it yay i'm ready
for academia right
um but that doesn't that doesn't change
what her negligence resulted in just
because i can explain it and i still had
to go through it
so her father died so she took the drugs
she took the alcohol meth was a that was
a fun one
so it's drug of choice she explained it
and uh
uh she abandoned myself and my brothers
when we were five
brothers right did you know that right i
don't
i haven't seen my brothers in 20 years i
don't know
but um
uh abandoned being abandoned by your
mother
is
let me let me make it worse being
abandoned by our mother and then the
whole of society telling you that
females never make mistakes
put those two things together what do
you get
what do you get when you have an entire
civilization that says it's your right
to choose abortion because female rights
right
what do you get when your mother
abandons you and then you're told oh she
should have aborted you
that would have been more convenient for
her right
well what do you get when you get that
what happens when uh
your mother drops you with random people
so she can go get high every fucking
night
so you have all of these concepts of
identity being used to
rationalize very bad actions
and they get away with it and they still
get away with it
to this day for as long as i've been
alive these sociopathic females
still get away with it and uh that's
entirely the fault of identity this
identity has created this sociopathic
eve
and it's uh and i was raised by one of
them
so i know how they go i know how they
think i know what happens when you give
that particular person full license to
engage in any whim of agency they want
uh and then they have the full
protection of the state and federal
morality
and culture and billionaires and
a bunch of scumbags in silicon valley
who enjoy their prostitutes to have
slightly higher iqs than the other ones
so it's i know these people i know all
these people
so um
it's frustrating having to deal with
that shit
because it's never changed it's always
been that way and it's probably not
going to change anytime soon
uh in fact it may accelerate to get
worse because all this stuff that we've
done to ourselves in america we're going
to export it to other countries you know
we're going to export it to islamic
countries i'm going to export it to
african countries i'm going to export it
to china
we're going to call that liberal
democracy we're going to say look how
equal we've made everybody
so you're going to see a lot more me in
the future a whole lot more me
i don't know if you all want that but
we're going to find out so
so one thing i was always curious
um about you uh and when you came on the
scene i think uh the rally point alpha
which was like a proto game b group
everyone was like oh is this homegrown
genius that's you know saying all this
crazy shit
uh there's a lot of excitement around
that um and there's always a sense that
you're like a lone wolf
this homegrown genius lone wolf type
type guy uh but you know there's also
some mystery you're alluded to some
connections uh
lee stranahan i think um you know uh
steve bannon's boy
um so yeah is are you a lone wolf
i have a very loose network
of people who if you put them all in the
same room they'd probably try to kill
each other
um i run the gamut from the far left to
the far right
my network is very vast i have like i
said i'm an ex-marxist so
i have those connections still and i
pal around with what people would
consider the far right a lot because of
the 4chan stuff
uh mostly larpers to be honest but
um you know i have those connections as
well i have connections
to countries where they are at war with
one another
i i i have a very large network and i
need the freedom of identity to bring
that network together
and transmute it into something useful
as long as identity remains and i cannot
do that
i'm unable to take these transmutation
chains and build the thing i need
because identity is actively stopping it
from happening
so in terms of lee
that is a that's a wild fucking story
how i got in with lee
um i wrote my book
i released it a very powerful person
read it
and she liked it this woman
i won't i can't mention her name and i
don't want to
she is probably one of the smartest
human beings i've ever met
period this is a person who was
born and bred in as powerful of a family
as you can imagine
one of the most powerful families
humanity has ever produced
she was raised by those people and she
liked my book and i liked the way she
thought i liked the way she approached
her problems
and i liked the way she never lost her
cool
i've never seen her loser cool and i've
seen her in some high stakes powerful
like
you know fuck around and you get you
know you lose
millions of dollars type things i've
always respected her and i still do to
this day
and uh she greenlit my book basically
she's like i'll walk you through
hollywood i'll walk you through all this
stuff this is fantastic stuff so she was
she was running point for me and it was
great but the problem
the problem here is the first page of my
book
that's the problem now as you know the
the book is
uh my it's my theory on
how ai will most likely evolve and how
you only need to capture emotions if you
want ais to do what we want them to do
but the first page of my book was
a synopsis of the ai
figuring out which events were
responsible for its own creation
so it's moving between four different
events four key events that it was able
to predict that if these events change
in any other way
then the ai would not have been created
to begin with so it's doing some
introspection on its own creation
and all of it was taken from my life
experiences each character was
me in the step of another person it was
another fragment of my brain
it wasn't uh pat ryan the person you're
talking to now it was
pat ryan as a priest pat ryan as an
arsonist pat ryan as these things and
then
merging two people together in pat ryan
plus this octopus you know uh different
different
different kinds of perspectives to build
these characters out
and the one character was the ceo of the
corporation
who built this ai and all the childhood
trauma he had to go through in order to
do it
and that first page of that book
was my ability to remember as much of
the abuse that i went through the sexual
abuse
as much of it now unfortunately it's
blacked out of my brain
so from five to
17 it was a blackout cognition has a
funny way of protecting you
and uh that first those first pages were
my
best attempt at writing it down as much
as i could remember
and that what i didn't realize
i was sending a signal to hollywood that
i was programmed
and i didn't even fucking know it
because they look for those people
they are looking for people who have
endured that level of abuse
they know that they can be uh you can
give suggestions to them
uh they know that they are uh pliable
and you can do that stuff and i was just
announcing with a
big red light didn't even realize at the
time a big red light that i was one of
those kids
and uh so they knew how to treat those
kids
they walked them right through the halls
of power of hollywood
because that's that's the recruitment
process i didn't realize that at the
time
but one of her pals and the cia
took a look at my book in 2007 and was
like
hmm this is some interesting stuff
we have an epid we have an epistemology
problem
i was like what do you mean the cia has
an epistemology problem what are you
talking about
like how do you even know that word it's
2007. like what is the problem here and
i had like
you know a couple of span of a couple
seconds i'm like
epistemology you have a science
knowledge problem
you're collecting too much data and you
can't make sense of it
and he was like how did yeah that's
exactly it
this is 2007 this is right when facebook
was about to go live and right when
twitter and all that social media stuff
was going live they they were
trying to solve for the the uh
epistemology problem of big data
how do you make sense of the noise and
my book proposed an answer
i said you don't need to collect the
data you just need to collect the
emotions
that's it once you have the emotions you
can predict people
you can create option trees huge option
trees of entire populations
and steer them and figure out where the
markets are going to go
you're no longer predicting at that
point once you have an emotional map of
the human destiny
you don't need to predict you you
literally make it happen you poke this
node which emotionally disrupts this
person which then disrupts this person
which then disrupts this person
and then now you're not predicting the
future you're literally controlling it
you're literally creating it through
emotions alone
now we're looking at this place now
where
the news is aggravating us and the ads
are aggravating us and guess what
things i wrote about they happened they
solved the epistemology problem
they made they started collecting the
emotions now they didn't
do it right i never told them how to do
it in full
my info brains were a key part of that
but i never gave that to them
so um from there
i got really good with her and then
i got to meet um a brilliant musician
brilliant musician who just really got
it he understood it i have a soft spot
for music
and his friend was lee stranahan's son
and uh me and shane have a very very
long
relationship we've we've done a lot
together and uh we've
we've solved all the world's problems by
now i'm sure um
but uh lee was was out there
doing his lee thing
and it was only a matter of time until
we started
tangling and talking and i'm on his show
every so often
he invites me up and
i was very big in the gamergate stuff
obviously so
uh please lee is
how do i put this when people see lee in
a room they run
in any one of these rooms in dc they
just run because they know
if if you are put in front of that dude
he's going to get info on you and you're
not going to like it
um it's not that he's malicious it's
just that he's real good
at getting that type of information and
juggling it all in his mind
he has an incredible incredible
knowledge of information that's just
sitting there ready to fire off at a
moment's notice
so you definitely don't want to add to
that you don't even get in the same room
with that guy if
if you're not okay with adding to that
list so
that's the story of lee i got there
through my hollywood connection
so i'm gonna share my screen right now
can you see this yep um
so i was wondering if you could walk us
through this again because i have some
follow-up questions
uh to recap uh you know pat was
mentioning how he bought a bunch of
followers for milo and this
kind of chain reaction occurred
yeah so yeah this is the transmutation
chain so
we start with milo milo was the
antithesis of the
um no he wasn't the antithesis he was
the mirror image of the sociopathic eve
so so the women who just get away with
everything he was using the exact same
mannerisms technique languages
everything it was
just like them but he wasn't one of them
and that was the problem he didn't fit
their identity pattern so
what i was able to do is say oh you know
what breeds
what breeds competition more than
emulation nothing if me and
if me and you are the same thing then
that's competition if i'm the complete
opposite of you that's kind of exotic
so he's i didn't want exotic i wanted
something that was identical to the
sociopathic female
and he was real dead close plus you know
he's funny
um but from a from that type of attack
vector that was
the psychological reasoning behind that
so picked him
and then i uh spoofed his uh
spoofed his follower count which then
flags all kinds of ais and
and bots and saying uh creature with
interesting properties that's exactly
correct
um and uh by spoofing his accounts
uh whenever you do that you get a bunch
of followers for tweeting something uh
people start looking they're like what
did you do how did you what's going on
here because that's
most reporters don't do that they don't
tweet and then they get like a billion
new followers they might get a million
like likes but who cares
um getting new followers is much more
proof of engagement
so poof you get the followers um
intercept i think he was with
the independent at the time uh bannon
came in and said yoink i'll take you
because bannon's just out there doing
culture war
bannon don't give a fuck bannon hates
you bannon hates me bannon hates bannon
bannon hates and he's fucking good at it
uh you're not gonna find anyone who's as
good as it as he is
he's a goddamn legend in that he's
amazing um
and he just wants he has his own vision
because he sees
certain enemies uh certain opposition
forces i should say
that are significantly going to
undermine what in his vision should be
the destiny of of america
and he's going balls out against those
people like
big balls out um there there isn't
whatever is on this planet he he can and
will turn into a weapon in that fight
there's there's nothing that can i can
stop that that's not gonna happen
see he gets picked and he starts flexing
his culture war muscle it works really
well
i mean we got the trump we know it
worked worked pretty damn well
um he was able to do the identity games
too through
you know the ai stuff with cambridge
analytic as you know he was on though i
think it was on the board there
for a bit um then trump
oh trump oh boy
um i spent a lot of my life in south
jersey
so we've known of trump
way before all of you you can't
do like i live 20 minutes from atlantic
city
so that's like that's where he made a
lot of his money he made all of his
money just like uh
doing casino stuff now the thing about
casinos is you can't do casinos in those
times
um they were you can't just walk up in a
casino be like i'm starting a new casino
it was illegal most states you couldn't
do it yeah atlantic city and las vegas
and that was
about it he had two spots now atlantic
city was formed because of prohibition
he had all these people they couldn't uh
they couldn't drink
so they would take the rail hop on down
from
philly and new york and whatever and
they'd come on down to atlantic city
where all the bootlegger docks were and
everything else and you get the liquor
and you so you have like the entire
generation of like
world war ii vets um
like their heyday was atlantic city when
they were like 20. like they'd come down
there and they'd drink that was their
drinking
uh their drinking hole and so you
he atlantic city like crazy money
because it's prohibition and it's all
illegal money too
um because you can't buy the shit so
what do you do with
what do you do with money uh from stuff
that you can't buy well you gotta
launder it
you gotta launder you gotta make that
money look legit now how do you do that
for the fucking casino
solve the problem all right so we solve
the problem of getting the flow of money
from the illegal product um we use
casinos great we did it
which means you can't just own a casino
even if it's allowed you can't just roll
up in atlantic city just drop a new
casino be like hey guys how you doing
i'm here for the competition
no you can't do that you can only get a
casino if you are mobbed the fuck
up period end of conversation so that's
mob ties
it's also a big reason why i left jersey
um but that's all mob shit
okay if we got if we got straight
mobster
in the white house now something went
wrong but not for the reasons you
suspect something went off the rails
somewhere someone fucked up royally and
they had to put
a pit bull in the white house to fix it
so that was a signal to me that shit was
about to get hot
i was like oh god they got the mob in
the white house
oh last time that happened was fucking
jfk i think
so okay something something's going on
here
um and you know although although
we all love the memes about trump and
all the rah-rah hate trump stuff
there's plenty of that for days you can
do that until you're bored in the face
you won't get any closer to actually
what's going on but at least you'll be
entertained
um then always
he's the guy that i'm sure most of you
don't recognize in the middle
uh the uh the arab in the middle
he is always
god always
was one of the wealthiest people on
the earth he was a major
holder of citibank a citigroup i should
say
he was one of the
largest owners single owners of shares
of twitter
he was um oil
you know oil money and the other thing
you gotta remember about away
is that he was trying to be peter the
great
of of saudi arabia so saudi arabia is
still doing its um
we have all the oil money so we don't
have to actually update our culture
thing
um and so there's still very much iron
age culture mentality
and plus um their holy site their
religion a lot of the holy
sites of that religion are in that
country so that country is kind of
predestined to be a very important
theological construct in and of itself
and so the people live those lives and a
lot of islam lives those lives as well
they
they look at medina they look at mecca
they have they have
those stories about muhammad um
and al-waheed was effectively trying to
be peter the great where he was trying
to modernize
saudi arabia and make it more liberal
and make it more western friendly and he
made a lot of friends in the west by
doing so primarily a lot of democrats
especially through citigroup
um one of the the woman i told you about
um with my book well
her family was citigroup big time
so awaid
away was doing some dumb things
in the name of trying to make saudi
arabia progressive
and you can rationalize that you can say
well i'm gonna i'm gonna make uh my
country modern i'm gonna make them free
i'm gonna make them
you know these western values right uh
and you can get a lot of trouble doing
that and he did
um the thing is when trump got elected
and uh
there were not a lot of people who were
happy about that now he was certainly
one of those people
because he may or may not have done some
really dumb things
in the name of trying to modernize saudi
arabia
so the las vegas shooting which was one
of those weird events where
it happens and then everybody forget it
happened like oh
we're just gonna shoot up 600 people
600 americans in saudi arabia and then
disappear all the witnesses the footage
and everything else and just i don't
know
what shooting what are you talking about
right uh well the shooters were firing
out of his penthouse
now you can't just go into an oil
sheik's penthouse and just pop
rounds off it's just not a thing you
don't just accidentally i'm just going
to pick this
i'll but i'm gonna pick this sweet fuck
it kick in the door
you know shoot up these windows that are
crazy bulletproof
bash them out and start popping
americans i'ma do that right
your chances of landing on his property
to do that
is slim to fucking zero there's no way
there's no way you would accidentally
just happen to be in his sweet popping
off rounds not a thing
so shortly after the las vegas shooting
this dude loses his entire extended
family
so uh there are a lot of people who
decided to say
you just can't kill americans we're
going to kill you and that's what they
did they rolled up
they rolled up his whole family shot him
in broad daylight uh interrogated a lot
of them
they hung this dude upside down for six
weeks in in the hotel and beat the shit
out of him
and at the end he was forced to cough up
six billion dollars and possibly
ownership of twitter as well
so he goes down he got ganked and that's
when i realized
oh god it's that bad everything has it's
gotten that bad to where
you can take down someone who's worth 18
billion dollars and get away with it bad
you just can't whack that dude and his
friends and walk away unscathed
he gets to spend his whole life plotting
revenge against you
the only reason you can do that is
because he fucked up
he fucked up bad and there's a lot of
people who either wanted him down
or were willing to abandon him when it
was his time to get answer for what he
did
so again you just can't whack
billionaires and get away with it they
got the resources to exterminate your
genome from the planet
and they've done this so for him to get
hit like that
boy that was a mega signal that was a
huge signal of how fuck the world was
you can't get away with that so how does
that lead to china
china needs oil that's it
china needs oil how do you how do you
get a modern country without oil
well you're gonna you're gonna make
solar panels i'm gonna make solar panel
panel tanks
i'm gonna have electric powered jets
give me that plant-based uh
give me that give me that plant-based uh
helicopter right the weapon's a war
you can't there's no there's no
environmental equivalent of those
weapons of war
elon musk isn't out there making you
know hybrid tanks
it's not a thing so i need oil to be
modern there's no way around it
and where's all the oil well it's not in
china it's in the south china sea it's
in the arctic
it's in siberia it's in iran it's in the
middle east
it's all over the place but what about
this oil why can't you just
go into an open market and buy it well
it's a cartel
it's opec opec has price controls on oil
you can only buy oil that is priced in
american dollars
and when you do that what you're doing
is creating artificial demand for the us
dollar
so our wonderful little utopia the
socialist experiment that we've been
doing and it is socialism it's socialism
for the rich and the poor
simultaneously because we have gone that
batshit with it
um this is
not funded by our productivity this is
not funded by our ability to do exports
this is funded exclusively by the
artificial demand of the us dollar
full stop that's it and where does that
demand for the dollar come from well it
comes from the demand of oil which is
priced in us dollars
to reserve currency the more of the
world modernizes
the more oil they demand the more oil
they demand the more us dollars they
need
to afford that oil and that's it
so in order for china to get its oil it
does not
want to buy american indexed oil because
if it did that
it would accidentally make us powerful
too
for every dollar of oil that they would
buy it would fund us
and china has a billion oil consumers
about to come online
so the more they grow the more we grow
and all we do is sit back and laugh
because all they do is buy the oil they
do all the work we just sit back and
collect the check
china doesn't want that deal admittedly
i don't blame them
but they were aggressive about it
they were trying to cut deals with iran
and destabilizing all these things and
opec was real pissed and there were oil
producers who want to sell that oil
at market rate they don't want it at the
indexing of the american dollar
they want to sell it to europe americans
we're paying like four dollars a gallon
what's european
like 12 7 12 a gallon right now
chinese will pay nine dollars a gallon
for it they'll happily pay that price
oil producers they want that they don't
want to sell to america
anymore and so what happens when you
step out of line well let's look at
saddam hussein we know what happened to
him let's look at gaddafi
we know what happened to him ah an
endless never-ending war for 17 fucking
years for my generation to be the
soldiers in by the way
so if you didn't if the 20 of us that
were aborted if you managed to get
through the
the slaughterhouse of the female vagina
um then you had the opportunity to uh
uh to go die in a war great awesome or
come back with fucking mental problems
or
who knows what they're doing to you so
great excellent cool thanks for the pipe
ride
life is great what a mess but this is
all because china wants oil
and china does not want to buy american
oil because it would accidentally
empower us and i knew that walking into
this game
the first thing i researched extensively
was um was the petro dollar
because it was after 2008 i needed an
explanation because marxism failed
as i said in my previous message and i
didn't get into the petrodollar
uh during that because that's literally
its own slide
because i'm still going on about it and
i still haven't finished yet so
um
i knew the petro dollar was the key to
explaining a lot of this behavior
that marxism just could not explain and
so i
i wrote about it maybe zerohedge cited
my work five fucking times about it
so i'm i i'm pretty credentialed guys
like
no i like i i took it seriously um
and i know that china did not want that
oil
and so uh they were going to step up and
step out of line and do
wild shit uh to get that oil and uh
eventually they were probably going to
piss off or embolden the people who made
china what it is
which leads us to our next character
which is henry kissinger
and i explained that history pretty
extensively in the last
part in the last episode so no need to
focus on that
but if you start going after kissinger
and friends you're going after
establishment
and if you go after establishment it's
one thing to wipe out
it's one thing to hang a billionaire for
six weeks upside down and kick the shit
out of them it's another thing to make
trillionaires disappear
making a trillionaire disappear results
in war guaranteed every time
there's no way around it that's why
robotic nationalism is so important
because in order to take out a
trillionaire
they have kills their kills like people
have kill switches they have dirt on
everybody
the kill switch of a trillionaire is a
destabilized planet
you kill one it's war period
so how do you dislodge trillion arabs
without getting the rest of us killed
because we're just human shields to them
so how do you do that well i need a war
that doesn't kill anybody
robotic warfare once you put robotic
warfare in play
yeah now i can touch trillionaires now i
can get them off the game too
poof away you go fuck off
because those are people that are
actually stopping us from getting into
space
there's no other way to address them so
transmutate chain all the way up to
whacking down the
specific trillionaires who have stopped
stopped us from taking the stars
so that's what this transmutation chain
was supposed to accomplish
so far it's working um but that next
part is going to be fucking ugly
all right um so i'm gonna pivot to some
questions
in the chat soon uh throw them in there
if you haven't already
uh question from daniel who's not here
today is um
would you trust you trust
i would trust me to do what i said i'm
going to do
yeah if if if i met me
and i was someone else i'd be like what
the fuck is this character
um this dude yeah of course i know i
know what i am
i'm not trying to pretend to be an
average person here
um would i trust me
in whole in general i don't
trust anybody in hole in general
maybe if the context was like a small
village and i was acting like this
it's probably a good reason to bring in
the shaman and some doctors and you know
let's talk it out
but while our dna is still in that small
village we're very much not
our technology is allowing us to do this
we're emulating a village
my dna doesn't like this very much
apparently so
um i would trust that i am uncomfortable
in the current space
about me that much is obvious um
about our current location in time
and place and what we're doing to each
other you can trust that i do not like
it and you can trust that i will act
against it
cool
hannah you had some questions
uh if you can pick one and
ask at the pat i have one that i picked
find it all right
my experience listening to you now and
last week is that of perceiving
a lot of pain and anger and i'm
still unclear as to how the content is
biasing
that perception since i've only felt
this
[Music]
to a much lesser degree before
uh last week and if my
perceptions are correct i think there
are some pretty good and valid reasons
you've listed for
why you might be feeling them but i
worry that if you
are that
those feelings could be acting for you
and detracting from your
sovereignty so i wonder
how you deal with that or if you do yeah
i don't have sovereignty
i still have it um
uh my my brain is kaleidoscope that's
that's one of the
byproducts of the abuse and the training
the kaleidoscope of your mind you
compartmentalize there's
a whole episode of my life i don't even
remember between
it's just blacked out so i don't have it
i don't have sovereignty
i have a loose network of cognitive
tricks and hacks and tactics
that keep me going forward but it's not
it's not as if it's my ego my will
at all times and i control every part of
my brain i've given that fight up ages
ago
there's almost no value in it so it's
not my way of excusing actions
everybody's
everybody's a lot everybody is
accountable for what they do to one
another even if you eliminate
morality we are still at the very
minimum accountable for
whatever reaction is coming our way
based upon what we put out there
i don't need morality for that um and
i'm not trying to evade it either
i'm simply stating that
uh did i go into the
was it with you guys did i go into the
um
eat laugh pray story about the demon did
i tell you guys that one okay i'll share
this one
so was it he laughed he left pray or
something like that that book i don't
remember what i was
it was a book um which i've never read
just to get that clear um eat pray love
thank you that one right so
eat pray love i've never read as you can
tell probably not my cup of tea but
uh the author gave a very fascinating
ted talk
um well i should say she spoke of one
particular point in her ted talk that i
found absolutely amazing
she was talking about the origin of
genius uh the
the word the animality the etymology the
thought process behind it
why uh why do we call each other
geniuses
uh she said it's a burden and she's
right um
if you are trying to say that you are if
i say someone's a genius if i say hannah
you're a genius
what i'm doing is i'm giving i'm giving
the curse of identity upon you
you are now expected to be a genius
because i have now called you that you
there's now an expectation where you
must be a genius
forever in every action you do in every
domain you encounter because i have
cursed you to identity so now guess what
you have
you have a pile of fucking anxiety
because there's no way every action
you're going to do
is going to be genius it's just not
possible that's not a possibility
it's only three pounds of meat there's
only so much you can perceive you can't
even do it all
so what the romans did uh was something
very fundamentally different they didn't
say that the human was the genius
they said you have genius that's a
that's one of those mistranslations uh
from playing telephone
over the centuries to say you have
genius they implied
that the divine manifested as a demon on
your shoulder
and then whispered the divine into your
ear
and then that was then compelling your
behavior and then the demon would
disappear
so if you did something great if you
like did this crazy dance and the whole
room was just like wow that was amazing
or you sung
and it was like wow that's great it's
because the demon
was channeling the divine through you at
that moment of time
and then it left so you don't have the
expectation to be
the thing just because you're allowed
you don't have the expectation uh the
identity is removed
by interpreting it that way and what
you're doing now is you're allowing
yourself
the freedom to be
inspired by the divine because if you
eliminate the
if you eliminate the identity barrier
the divine can happen to you at any
given moment and you're free to go
through it because you know it's
sitting on your shoulder you know it's
just commandeering you at that moment in
time
no sovereignty needed no agency needed
it's just it's coming out
and um if you allow yourself to be in
that space where you give that demon its
ability to move um you'll
you'll experience life very very
differently i
for example all the terrible stuff that
i talk about
and all the the abyss uh working that i
do
i'm i've never experienced depression in
my life
not one fucking second i don't even know
what it feels like
couldn't even tell you i have a lot of
anger and people can say oh that's
you know that's depression but i've
never sat down and said oh man
i don't have the will to do this thing
i've had an abundance of will because i
have anger
but that's me also the key to that is to
say
i'm not an identity i'm not a genius i'm
not these things
i am whatever you know i
i'm not out here trying to control my
brain and micromanage it
this is i have the agency to be inspired
by the divine
that's an important part of who i am and
uh
so anyway um
that's what i do with the anger that's
uh
why you may be perceiving it um because
i
i let the divine channel through me
whenever it has to
and i i don't attribute that to my
personality it's just one
that's one part of it
i got to follow up there um that was a
really great ted talk
uh but she used the word daemon your
dame on your guiding spirit
and and you kept saying demon yes sorry
this translation
yeah i'm curious do you you distinguish
between the two or do you think there's
multiple
kind of energetic forces that influence
us
i think when it comes to that um
it could be external divine it could be
um the divine
of of cellular memory as well like uh
take a
take the adaptation of the cell the dna
all the all the lessons
of of evolution are encoded at the
geometric level
whether it's dna helix whether it's a
cell membrane uh
all the lessons are are there in a
geometric space
and that geometric space changes over
time to adapt to different
configurations and whatnot
so to sort of to say that uh the divine
can only come from outside that's not
true it can also come from the cells
so the cellular structure is a lesson
it's not just you i mean technically
cell is the only thing that's actually
alive and everything is derivative of
that
but the the cell has the limitations
just as the brain has the limitations
of of its shape and its size and its and
its um
and um what it is
trying to solve for it's it's giving you
suggestions what it's made for because
of its shape
and so when those those shapes they
carry it's not memories it's the wrong
word
but they carry god
i don't want to i'm just going to
anthropomorph i'm going to
anthropomorphize it right so
it's whispering these cells are
whispering
their suggestions to you and it's not
always the willpower that's at play here
these cells all their lessons it's
constantly this aggregate whisper
that is saying you're going to go in
this direction or
you find this person attractive or you
like doing this behavior it's not a
conscious thing
um so the divine can come from the
actual previous lessons of our ancestors
as well
and those lessons are encoded quite
literally at the physical space of the
cell
so there's like a cellular memory i
think that's where a lot of the
a lot of the what we call divine is
really coming from
jordan you had a
trying to contextualize all of this
stuff
um i guess my question
mostly relates to your blackmail economy
presentation
so i found it very revealing that you
are mentioning
uh having experienced abuse
uh you seem to have implied that it's
ritualized or uh
involves training i'll let you go into
that as you wish but
i had been sensing that you had more
than a passing
experience with it uh perhaps something
personal
based on the way that you're talking
about it
my question is the conclusion you draw
in your blackmail economy piece uh
i want to put this delicately seems to
imply
that you propose a continuation of it as
opposed to a succession of it
um as somebody who considers what you
seem to have gone through is probably
the highest evil
how exactly are you arriving at the
conclusion that
that the destruction of that dynamic
is a bad thing ah it's bad thing if it's
mismanaged
this is a little it's a little bit of a
tactical play um it can be
and should be and i'm just waiting for
the goddamn call so i can actually
destroy it all
um just to interject i i just want to
point out that
to somebody who's coming into it it
really does seem like you're saying
hey this is fucked up that this is a
thing
but uh we need to maintain the dynamic
which in my mind would almost
automatically involve
continuing abusing children so to uh to
be fair i don't state those words
exactly
and i'm curious about the chain of
reasoning that you're using there
because what i'm doing is i say this is
i'm saying this is what's going on and
here's a proposed attack against it and
when you launch that attack there are
two possible outcomes
so it's it's uh if i didn't make that
clear then that is
that is the intention behind that i
should probably spell that out a bit
more
um but on the other hand if you attack
and you fuck up
you will not be able to attack again
they will adapt they will double down
and they will lock the whole shit down
and they will continue doing this
forever
is that what's going on with the
epstein-maxwell affair right now
that's just been mismanaged it leaked
into public and now
uh they're scrambling not mismanaged
that leak all of that was intentional
um when you're like i said hunting
trillionaires is not an easy thing
hunting trillionaires is the most
difficult sport you could possibly
possibly ever engage in because there's
too many chess pieces
way too many chess pieces so you want to
make sure that when you do something
you have thought well in advance about
all as many complicated outcomes as you
possibly could
and have reactive forces in place to
manage them and steer them back into the
main story
because again if you fuck up they adapt
and they will learn
we know what happens if epstein goes
free we know what happens when
um when galen goes free all their
buddies they won't laugh they won't say
ha ha we pulled one over you they'll say
fuck that was close we need to get
better at this
and they'll get better at it so you need
to make damn sure that your kill shot's
an actual kill shot
or you're fucked
all right um i put you on you jordan uh
uh we're gonna get to another question
so uh
coops you had a uh question
above you can you gonna meet yourself
and read it
yeah i was just curious uh
what some euphemisms would be
what would be contained in a supposed
icarus dead man switch
uh what kinds of things did william turn
though change your mind oh no
i liked that podcast with him that you
did and
you know sweeping into
your blackmail inflation uh
you know talk is that still running
you know behind the scenes is that
controlling the nuclear game which is
you know basically power on the world
stage is that
is that the puppet master is is it black
male or is it something
else or deeper connected uh
yeah oh did you go there thanks yeah
yeah yeah um so the
the like i can answer all those
questions in one answer i believe
so
what is a central bank a central bank is
a central account of all transactions
meaning it is one source of authority
all the transactions that move in
all the transactions that move out is
stamped with my authority and there is
no contesting authority to it
there's nobody out there saying i'm also
a central bank ha ha look at me i can
i can get around this guy because he's
an asshole so use my banking accounting
instead
that leads to messes according to the
world rulers and the managers of things
and
administratively speaking it's easier to
have one source of authority
a central bank does that now each nation
has their own central bank yes
but then there's uh the bank of
international settlements and
they resolve all of the tensions between
the central banks and then you have imf
an international monetary fund a world
bank so you have these
management forces that are com steering
these central bank decision-making
policies what how much money they put in
the economy how much money do they pull
out of the economy
this is very important to get right
because if you do it wrong you get
hyperinflation and get like you know
nazi germany
or you get a depression and you get
1930s fdr land so
it's a it's a it's careful it's a
careful balancing act
and that's where the problems start it's
a balancing act now i've been a
programmer for 20 years
and if you know any programmers one god
bless you they need all the help we can
get and two
they are they experience
the folly and the hubris of the
architect
um that's their job where um
the program has has very simple rules
has maybe
you know 20 30 rules uh but you can
build these infinitely
complicated variations from those rules
and application is a massively
complicated beast
where you you you deal with a lot of
exceptions and a lot of
rules and a lot of a lot of these sorts
of things and you're on the hook for
every line you
write so every time you write a line of
code that code is not going to get
pulled out later on
or ever really most code rarely gets
overwritten
instead people solve their code by
adding more code that's actually an
easier way to do it because undoing code
is expensive it's like undoing law
uh you have to undo all the institutions
and you have to undo all the other laws
and the correlating laws and the social
programs and all this other shit well
code is the same exact problem
now um as you
go through and you architect this thing
where you have total freedom to
architect it
you're now on the hook for everything
you've previously done every rule that
you've made you're now on the hook for
and you're infinitely trying to resolve
a consistency between this stuff
so you're going to make mistakes you're
going to make mistakes there's going to
be bugs
there's going to be problems right well
the same is true for a central bank
the same is very true for a central bank
they're going to make mistakes but what
does the mistake of a central bank look
like
well two mistakes two categories of
mistakes one
the money is leaking somewhere it's not
going where it's supposed to go so if
you think of a central bank as like
pipes connecting policy to money volume
all right what happens if that pipe is
leaky where does the money accumulate
well it's not going to the social
program it's not going to the
the purchase agreements it's not going
to bond purchases it's going fucking
somewhere
but where is it going well someone
figures it out let's say someone comes
along and says oh i found that money
does he run to the central bank hell no
that's free money
bro that's free fucking money i am not
going to tell the central bank that i
found a leak in your system
you know give me a pat on the back go go
me
no i just found a bottleneck i just
hacked your system i got free money
and the thing is the thing is i kept you
using that maybe you got too flashy
maybe you bought too many too many uh
porsches or you got too many rolexes and
you're really peacocking it pretty hard
and you're not hiding it very well that
you got rich suddenly despite the fact
that you were a janitor three months ago
so you you get lucky you hit the fucking
lottery
so he said in the shootie boys shooty
boys they're looking at you real
suspected they're like
you know this dude's uh he's bawling
pretty hard we should probably look into
that that's probably indicative of us
fucking up
so we need to we got to look into that
so he looks into it
and i go to this guy and i say hey guy
you know jig is up
i know what you're doing uh he says oh
shit you're fucking up my free money
here now if he wasn't properly prepared
or wasn't properly defended
uh he has to you know serve time in
prison and that type of shit but
but he has blackmailing people
blackmailing a central banker politician
actor
athlete corporation he ain't going to
jail
he's not going to jail so that person
figures out
the leaks in this central banking system
and he can't be taken out of it
so you have a parasite this is how you
create a financial parasite
a parasite sits there sucking from the
mistakes of the architects
pulling all the money out spending it
however they will and how do they
rationalize it
they say well we won't be too greedy
we'll put the money where you intended
to send it but we're gonna take our cut
okay that's just one parasite i've
explained how you build one parasite
from a central bank
you can scale this out to hundreds of
thousands of parasites
millions in fact millions doing the same
exact shit
taking these inefficiencies of the
central banking system
and lining their pocket with it
now eventually if you have too many
parasites the host dies
so you need to start coordinating the
parasites
because they might accidentally kill the
host too so instead of arresting these
people and pulling them out of the
pipelines which you're not going to be
able to do
not mostly at least you need to change
your
mode of operation much differently you
need to say okay
we're all going to have a council of the
parasites and we're going to have a nice
talk
about how we don't accidentally kill the
free money supply that we just all
stumbled upon in our own ways
so we need just as there's a central
bank
we need central crime
because that's how you don't kill the
host accidentally
so what does that central crime look
like could be the drug trade
it could be human trafficking could be
all kinds of stuff see the parasites
they move with this money that's
unaccountable
and you need to have something that can
absorb all the money that they can't
spend
because they might accidentally kill the
host if they don't
so where do you pull all that money
there's only a few things in the world
that can absorb that level
of parasite driven money there's only
we're talking hundreds of billions
probably trillions a year
probably even more than that there's
only a handful of human organizations
that can absorb that level of money and
it's not a corporation corporations
can't absorb that
only a state can absorb that
only a nation can absorb that
why because it's expensive to build on
asia it's part of one of the most
expensive things you could do
you have to you have to fund the
soldiers and they fund the workers and
you got to build the roads and
that's a lot of spending that's a lot of
spending now you can't just
get just fund any nation you got to pick
a nation that's really expensive to
develop
can't just like you know drop a drop a
line to this laundered parasite money to
russia because they have natural
resources they have stuff they could
actually sell
no no no no you got to pick a nation
that is almost impossible
to cultivate that is surrounded by its
enemies
that is full of no water that is
completely covered in deserts
i can't name names you might have an
idea
all right some explosions in the zoom
room right now
um so we'll uh
we'll uh close off with a few more
questions
um uh
my question is relevant peter how do you
know your question is
um yes we'll go with jacob and then
we'll end with key
so jacob you had a question
so everybody plays false
sometimes or in other words everyone
bses right
that means ibs sometimes
less and less that means
patrick you bs sometimes too because
you're one of us right
so i'm this is less of a question than
just calling you on some serious bs
playfully man like i appreciate you
you're clever dude i like listening to
you
um but if you face
the full spectrum of evil
you don't come out angry
you come out in a whole lot worse shape
or maybe better shape
but you don't come out angry it's the
last thing you come out
thank you
is that true
well the good news is um there is always
new layers of human depravity that i
have yet to
explore that is true
anger
is a fuel it's um
it's a reminder that you have to do
stuff it's like uh it's like this
nagging
like yeah you should do the thing to do
the dishes right the anger will drive
you into action
because what's the alternative to sit
and think and that's okay it's okay to
sit and think every so often
um
but you can't think forever because
you eventually die you just run out of
time and all
of the things that you could have done
you weren't able to do or you couldn't
do
and so when you're dealing in that full
spectrum space
and this is me stating that yes there
are levels of depravity that i have
intentionally refused and there are
levels of depravity that i have not been
exposed to that can get
real bad real quick um
but with that said
uh people call it bullshit i call it
noise security
so noise security is an important part
think of um
think of uh celebrities when they uh
they they say
certain things like kanye west for
example right so kanye west is always on
twitter doing some shit
he's always just saying something wild
right that's noise security you can't
actually get kanye west from his tweets
you may think you do you feel like you
do you think you figured out the kanye
puzzle
she didn't there's noise security and
you're looking here instead of there
right
i do a lot of noise security there's a
lot of shit that i put out there that is
intentionally wrong
and i have to do that because there are
people constantly trying to find
information about me
constantly i've had new york times send
opposition research on me
yeah fucking when's the last time you
got hit by oppo research of new york
times
good luck so you need noise security so
what do i do i feed them dirt i feed him
fake dirt on me
oh i was here i was beating this black
kid ha ha look at me i'm such a racist
right
so i feed him that and then they go
wasting all their resources and cycles
on that
they say oh he's close to bannon he must
know this i say okay i guess i guess on
him so i just throw noise on that too so
i had all these journalists looking out
for all this info on me it's all
bullshit
so yeah noise security is a really
important part of it now in terms of my
core and my soul and my essence
like i said i said i don't have
sovereignty i know i don't have
sovereignty
um so to me i'm i'm just a
function i mean i've stated that many
times on twitter that's probably the
truest thing i ever put out there i see
myself as a function
input is life output is getting the fuck
off this rock
um there's plenty of people out there
who are happy or working on happiness
let them be that they're they're they're
better at happiness than i'll ever be
and i don't fault them for that i don't
you know i'm not jealous of that
everybody has what they do very well
some people do happy very well i don't
do happy very well
i don't do it at all almost
so uh yes things can always be worse
i do use noise security and
uh you know i'm
i'm just one person who thinks i got the
alchemy right
and if i got it wrong i just go back to
being poor
i came from poor and go back to being
poor i know to solve that that's easy
but then you know i just live a life and
i die and whatever maybe i get to love
someone maybe i don't
maybe i can jump on tinder and
jesus christ it's a disaster nowadays i
hear i don't know
i don't know i just don't do happy very
well i wasn't trained to do happy
so i don't know how to do it so
very good at anger though i hope that
answers something
all right key bring us home
hi pat hello
speaking of getting off the rock also
thank you peter um i know i made a big
deal about like
the last question or whatever but i
actually really appreciate
it right now um for the things that have
been talked about so
uh and thanks to everyone here as well
for being here um i guess i
needed to say that yeah okay um
the question comes from you saying that
your output is to get off the rock
so i just wanted to maybe ask you to go
into that a little bit like the uh the
neanderthal brain project
so my curiosity in this is because of my
i mean i'm interested in psychology a
lot and the brain itself
um so what part of the brain or the
biology are you experimenting on
and the other part was yup uh
mars 2020 wow um
how do you feel about it yeah
um
that's the first question that's the
first time someone has asked me about
the brains
let me see i'm doing this it's like like
20 episodes 20 episodes in is the first
actual near with all brain question
because we keep drinking every time i
know
um okay
so brief history
of why every single attempt at space
we've done
has failed and is destined to fail um
figured out the first rockets in like
1920 i think
and uh the germans got really good at it
and the americans are like hey you germs
are pretty good at it be ashamed if you
die at a war trial so why don't you
you know just work for us instead and uh
they said hey that's a pretty good deal
and so von braun comes over and helps uh
nasa basically right
so he's you have some nazis running
around and giving us their technology
and uh
go us russia got their own uh their own
nazi guys
they got a lot of interesting math
people we didn't take we didn't take the
math people and that that fucked us i
think in the long run the russians have
much better mathematics than we ever
will
um but uh and it's entirely from
from that split after world war ii so we
tried the space thing
and what what is you know why did space
happen in the 60s what does it
do economically first if i'm an economic
plane if i'm an economic planner
and my and my currency is overheating
it's it's it's
very much in demand but i have to print
only so much of it because my dollar is
pegged to gold i can't just freely print
my money
something has to absorb the hot money
and at that time our
our dollar was actually pegged to gold
around the 1960s it severed in 1970 went
over than a petro dollar
so i have i have a huge incentive to
keep my economy in balance and
and the presence of my dollar imbalance
so i need a big heat sink just like the
central banks that create central crime
if i have a managed economy i need
something that can absorb all of the
extreme
amounts of money that i'm about to print
space program was it it first served as
a function to absorb all that hot money
that was his job and it did humongous
amounts of
money i mean stupendous an appetite a
pit of just
fire that just absorbs and destroys
money um
and that was its function i mean that's
it's like economically speaking that's
its function
it's scientific research was a great
output the r
d stuff that it paid for was fantastic
the laser comes from that computer uh
certain computer stuff comes from that
as well did a fantastic work the r d
side that was a happy side effect
and getting space was eh and maybe you
know put some people on a rock
or whatever but that's uh that was the
huge justification and so what that did
in all of our minds is it settled the
argument once and for all only the state
can get us into space
because only the state commands the
money and they have the incentive and
they use the economic uh
uh either multiplier or destroyer of a
space program to do so
so then the military gets involved
and they're like hey orbital dominance
is kind of important because sputnik
happened and what the fuck
uh why is that why is that satellite up
there beeping at us like
what like we need to we need to do
something about this
and so now orbital dominance is
important so if an any other nation
decides to try and build their own space
program oh wow look at that their
capsule blew up that's weird oh their
landing pad doesn't work oh
they're having electric ah they lost
their electricity that's so strange
orbital dominance is a real important
part of us military doctrine
um and so we've actually put ourselves
in a trap
where india and china are in a much
better position than america is
and it's fucking bad uh it's bad for the
us military
and as a result it's bad for uh global
stability in the
in the sense in which we have it now
although there are alternative models of
global stability
for starters we only leverage the public
sector
so very soon you're going to learn
that the amount of money laundering that
nasa was doing was stupendous
that information is coming out in
probably like a couple weeks maybe a
month from now or two
but you're gonna learn that nasa was
doing serious fucking money laundering
and not going out to like doing the
space program shit and stuff like that
um there'll be more details on that
later but
the the the key thing is that when it
comes to china and india
they can leverage both the state and the
private sector
to go into space so they can leverage
their corporations to do it we have like
a handful of corporations
owned by a couple you know soon-to-be
trillionaires uh we put a lot of pr
on them and they're going to solve all
of our problems but i've been to spacex
i've seen their shop
i see how they work um it's a it's a
three shift process
day and night they have to manufacture
all their stuff in-house in country so
that means like chip fab and all this
other shit because they can't trust
china they can't actually go out to
international vendors and build their
stuff because space
spacex is they get a billion dollars a
year from the air force
yeah most people don't know that so they
get a guaranteed grant because the the
air force consolation is two billion
dollars a year to run
and elon basically said yeah i'll cover
you know just give me half of that and
i'll i'll reduce your costs
he said okay there it is so now they
just save 50 of their budget
awesome uh and then eli is out there so
so when you're playing with these powers
and and these like tremendous
forces of nature and just and just to
harp on the elon bit again
he was concerned he wasn't going to hit
a certain deadline so he wanted to
leverage
an alternative means of launch i forget
what what launch this was but
he um he went to there is a union i
i kid you not there is a union of ship
of of spaceship
owners i don't know what it's called uh
but there's actually like people who own
spaceship launches and spaceships
themselves and so elon went through
these people and said i need a backup
rocket in case my production doesn't
work because he was still like
experimental and
uh that type of stuff and they looked at
him and they saw all the star power that
was elon musk's and us and they figured
hey you know you're rich
bilky for everything so they said 600
million dollars
600 million dollars for a fucking launch
eli was like
elon said fuck that fuck you never
dealing with you guys again
right so and then there's satellite
insurance and that's fucking satellite
insurance so like
elon musk's number one play at
dominating space
is to intentionally blow up his ships
that's the smartest thing he could do
because every time a ship blows up he's
going to wipe out the satellite
insurance market
he's going to completely crush it and so
when you play that game
it just wipes out his competitions he
there's nobody that can even afford the
risk to launch
you have to use the old school tactics
of doing everything in triplicate
to build like three of everything every
damn prototype you come up with which is
still somewhat done today but satellite
insurance is a big part of reducing the
risk of launching to begin with
every time his ship blows up and usually
like satellite
insurance payouts is all money in no
money out because ships don't blow up
because nasa's in charge
but he's just blown shit up left right
and center doesn't give a fuck so as a
result he's
dumping he's emptying those those
coffers that that's no longer a
profitable market
um but um but uh
anyway the point is there are severe
imbalances in how america does space
anymore
it's it's it's turned into this like
catastrophic byzantium mess of
policy and and funds and it's just it's
it's
a total disaster so as a result the
chinese and the indians are going to
leapfrog us pretty fucking hard
so i'm looking at this like okay guys
we've we're
it's obvious to me now why we're not in
space more now it's laid bare i get it
um so i realized that okay well maybe
putting the er the nerds and the
eggheads in charge was the bad idea
because now it's the actuaries and the
accountants that are in charge
and that's also a bad idea because um
i think there was a former director of
nasa he came out and stated
uh this is almost like we're building uh
ships in the 1500s filling it full of
supplies and people
launching it all across the horizon and
telling it to stop and come back
it's like that's a stupid model that's
absolutely that's a ridiculous model
those ships have to do something they
have to come back
packed with something either spices or
money or
soldiers or something otherwise why are
we building these damn ships
so i looked at that and i'm like oh okay
well you need a labor force
that's it once you have a labor force
you can take space
now there's profit in it there's one
asteroid that's flying around
it's about 100 million tons of platinum
it's worth 4
trillion trillion t trillion dollars
that one asteroid that's it um
so if you were able to field the labor
force that can go get
that asteroid uh you have just
fundamentally changed
capitalism you have changed capitalism
in a way that marx cannot even envision
you will make every socialist look like
a fucking lazy pile of shit that they
actually are
because what this does is you said we're
going to redirect the capital flows away
from making another dog walker app
fuck you silicon valley and we're
actually going to do something useful
like collect goddamn asteroids
and bright and the byproduct of that is
we're going to create the infrastructure
to keep doing it
and we're going to have the labor forces
that can actually do it
things can't send humans in space
because we suck at it we absolutely
terribly suck at it they don't tell you
when humans come back from
um from high orbit their brains are
they're not working their brains have
problems
so what happens um they have
life has this one signature that's
guaranteed no matter where it starts on
any planet
whether they use dna whether to use
carbon whether you use any other
material doesn't matter
all life has the lesson of gravity built
into it
there's no way to escape that it is a
constant of the universe
no matter what alien evolves no matter
what happens gravity is a key
part of its evolutionary cycle and if
you deprive that life
of the gravity that it grew up in over
billions of years
that life isn't going to function pretty
well and expands right expanse goes into
that pretty heavily
so humans as the labor force in space is
not possible
but what makes humans such a good labor
force to begin with it's not our hands
it's the fact that we can talk to each
other otherwise we'd send
fucking giraffes into space to mine for
us can't talk to giraffes
to send humans up there because they can
listen to us and they can understand our
plans and our organizational tactics
but we're not the only hominid not
anymore
bring them back let them go into space
harden them get their brains ready for
space get those neanderthals ready for
that
because we can't experiment on each
other we have too many laws and moral
qualms and
issues with each other to politicizing
everything because we're stuck in this
identity trap
so let's send someone who isn't trapped
in identity
who's been asleep for 400 000 years
let's wake his ass up
and saying hey buddy you're going to
save us you're going into space
you're going to be the labor force we're
going to go we're doing it
so you solve the labor force you solve
the demand for
um what space has to offer you
fundamentally change the capital flows
of the planet
you can now wipe out trillionaires who
don't play fair
uh i have everything i need i just need
time and i gotta survive
all the enemies i've made so we'll see
how that goes i'll let you know in four
months
okay um yeah there's
questions but i think it's pretty
intense here um
so pat uh people are asking was there is
this the end of season two is there
season three coming up
um so yeah what any closing thoughts
uh and what's your sense about uh season
three
season season one was exploring
the weird future that we're about to
walk into
when you start whacking trillionaires
and getting away with it when you start
coming up with uh
losing our sentience on monopoly and all
the weird gene tech that's coming
what does that mean for morality what
does that mean for law it opens up those
questions it doesn't have a lot of good
answers
but it certainly does open those
questions um the one answer i'm backing
is
the the weirdness of ai warfare at the
very end of it with gnostic warfare
uh which is the last episode of season
one season two was going into
the the what i call the blue church
but it is one of the most predominant
factors in preventing that future from
happening in an orderly fashion
because they're going to haphazardly
reactively try to stop every step of it
along the way
and they've been doing this for a long
time it's almost like autopilot it's not
a plot to stop this type of stuff but
they they keep accidentally smothering
this stuff and it's cradle and i'm i'm
uh i don't have the patience for it
anymore so in season two i lay out
exactly how to do that
how to actually get around some of these
things call them out on
their operations how to deal with the
leviathan
when it slams into you how to make sense
of cthulhu like
fucking entities that don't even
understand themselves um
so season two is all of that now
there's no rule that says a season has
to be me talking and you listening in
fact that's not a
that's not a that's not something i have
terrible experience with and i'm
to be honest makes me a bit
uncomfortable uh i like having an
interactive
relationship with people i like people
being able to tell me things i don't
know
or give me perspectives i don't have
remember i hate identity i like being in
the real i like being in the is
so season three is not going to be a
presentation
season three is going to be interaction
i'm inviting you to my server everyone
here
this is a server it's a it's a slack
clone
in that server there are a series of
chat rooms that are already opened up
now the thing is as you talk more of the
server will open up based on your
interests
so if you start talking about
neurochimera suddenly you'll be brought
into the neuro chimera channel
you'll be like oh there's a conversation
going on here
so season three is about discovering the
server
how much of the game that i make how
much of it did i plan out
and you gotta find it
all right and that link is in the chat
by the way
all right everyone uh pat thank you uh
for season two of dark stoa uh if you'd
like to give a gift
to pat you can go to this website right
here
if you'd like to support the stoa go to
patreon it's probably not wise to have
patreon
hosting the most dangerous on the
internet but you know there you go
um yeah you can go to a website to check
out
other upcoming events at the stoa so
thank you everyone
for coming out tonight thanks folks